Stop giving agents execute_sql. Give them reviewed business actions instead.
Raw database MCP can hand SQL text, table selection, filters, and write authority to the model.
Synapsor binds tenant and principal scope from trusted context, outside model arguments.
The reviewed contract declares visible fields, kept-out fields, bounded writes, and approval.
The model sees two semantic tools. It does not see raw SQL, credentials, approval, or apply.
The inspect tool reads one tenant-scoped customer and records evidence. The source stays unchanged.
The agent requests a plan credit. Runner stores the exact diff, evidence handle, and expected row version.
Before approval, Postgres still shows zero credit. Proposal does not equal commit.
An operator reviews and approves outside the model-facing MCP surface.
Guarded writeback checks approval, primary key, tenant, allowed columns, row version, and affected rows.
The receipt and replay preserve the read, evidence, proposal, approval, writeback, and result.
The same canonical contract is pushed to Synapsor Cloud as an immutable version with a server digest.
The Cloud registry exposes the reviewed boundary and exports a secret-free Runner bundle.
Try the open-source Runner. Synapsor Cloud is available for design partners.